Oscar Torres

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Profile

Passionate software engineer, open to learn as much as I can, Committed to utilizing my skills to further the mission of a company. Knowledgeable in modern JavaScript (ECMAS6+), Typescript, React, Redux, Express, NodeJS and MySQL. Able to effectively manage pre-processors as LESS and SASS as much as pure CSS. Bilingual.

Experience using Styled components (React), consuming APIS (JS) and CSS frameworks as tailwind for responsive designs.

Employment History

Semi Senior React Engineer, The Estée Lauder Companies Inc

FEBRUARY 2022 - PRESENT

Worked with micro-services and a huge infrastructure supporting more than 400 different sites.

- I got to develop with Drupal and Perlgem for my first time.
- Created new reusable components for LATAM sites.
- Actively participate in the refactor of on-boarding procedures to make it easier and more efficient for the new-comers to understand it.

Front end engineer, The Body Shop & Tailorsoft, Remote

FEBRUARY 2021 - FEBRUARY 2022

Worked in The Body Shop as a Front end engineer getting a promotion after my first month.

Discussed technical requirements and estimates while code reviewing work from my peers.

- Got my first promotion after my first month for exceeding expectations according to my manager.
- Increased the code's readability and project stability by implementing end-to-end tests with Cypress.
- Increased the test's coverage by creating new tests and refactoring existing ones to cover more features with Jest and react-testing-library.

Full Stack developer, SIICOING, Cali

JUNE 2020 - FEBRUARY 2021

- Redesigned the front-end to make the UX friendlier to the users and got a very good feedback from the users.
- Sped up the processes and performance of the application.
- Organized and prioritized work to complete assignments in a timely, efficient manner.
- Maintenance of MySQL databases

Education

Full Stack Developer, Henry, Remote

NOVEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

- JavaScript and ECMAS6+
- React

Details

+57 (304)-528-8108 oscardtorres@hotmail.com

Portfolio

Portfolio

<u>GitHub</u>

LinkedIn

Weather-App Project

Languages

Fluent in English

Native in Spanish

Skills

Agile and Scrum

React

Redux

Mobx

Express.js

Git

NodeJS

Cypress

Jest

- Redux as a state management library.
- NodeJs
- Express
- Relational databases SQL
- Gi

Advanced course of React, Platzi

AUGUST 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021

Reinforced knowledge on React Hooks, testing with Jest and Cypress, common design patterns for React and styling with styled components

Courses

Basic course of Python, Platzi

SEPTEMBER 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021